In this video, I'll introduce the get diff command and we'll also learn how to read, how to make sense
of its output, which can sometimes be a bit confusing when you're starting out.
So they get diff command is all about showing changes in get so in a given repository.
There are many situations where we might want to know what changed between the last comment and our
working directory, what's changed between the staging area and the working directory, what's changed
between two branches or two different files over a certain number of commits?
What's changed between what we have locally versus what's on GitHub, all these different scenarios
where we may want to learn about changes, about comparisons so they get diff command?
Does that the get diff command is powerful, but also sometimes a bit overwhelming when you're starting
out.
It doesn't do anything to the repository.
It doesn't impact anything just like git status and get log.
It's purely an informative command.
So it's more about just taking a peek at changes and trying to understand how things have changed.
OK, so over here I've got a pretty large git repository.
I'll just show you there's a bunch of comments.
There's a decent number of files.
So lots of comments here, lots of files, html since he says some JavaScript and currently I haven't
changed anything since the last Kimmett right on Branch Master up to date.
OK, so then let's say I spend a couple of hours making some changes.
I'm going to fast forward, but I'll show you an example.
For whatever reason, I decide, you know what, I want this colour to be magenta and this other colour
should be to go a Cyane.
I'm just going to use like labelled named colours.
So they're easier to identify instead of, you know, this.
Let's do Korrell there anyway.
I'll make a bunch of changes.
Maybe I'll also change some HTML.
So in this HTML page, I'm going to change this one to say hey there and then down at the bottom I'll
make a paragraph and just says chicken's all right.
And then I go to this JavaScript file grid.
Yes.
And somewhere maybe in the middle I'm going to print out a happy face.
OK, and then back in a ceasefire, I changed some font size from 35 pixels to 65 pixels and let's say
I do a whole bunch more, but this is just enough for this demonstration.
And I then realized, you know what, I should probably make a commitment.
I don't remember exactly what I did in each of those files.
So if I just go back and look at this file, it's not immediately clear what's changed unless I memorized
or I exactly know what the file looked like, it's difficult to pinpoint exactly where things changed
across these three files.
So that's where DIFC comes in.
The first usage of git diff.
It's just get spaced diff without any additional options.
And this will list all the changes in our working directory that are not staged for the next commit.
So it compares the staging area and our working directory.
So I'll show you an example.
Currently I have not staged anything for comments, right.
If I type status.
We see that there are three modifications, three different files, none of them staged, and if I run
this, get diff command.
We see this kind of crazy looking output's, it's another one of these windows where I'm not actually
in my terminal, I have to.
Well, I guess I am, but I have to escape this view by typing queue, just like with jet lag.
So, anyway, I see all of this and it's a little bit crazy looking at first.
We see some of the stuff that changed.
We see some red, some green minus and pluses.
But then what is this is at signed negative 25 comma seven minus minus minus plus plus plus.
It's all this stuff.
I mean, it's just kind of crazy looking, but this is the output of get diff.
So what I'm going to do in the next video is walk you through how to read this, how to make sense of
what's going on here, what's this line doing, what's the minus and the plus mean and all that stuff
that's coming up.
But this is just an introduction to the concept.
You make a bunch of changes, then you want to try and understand more about what those changes were.
And this is one use case.
Forget dif.
We just don't really know how to make sense of it yet.
So that's the next video.