The next version we'll look at is get dif head, so this will list all changes in our working directory
since the last commit since hit, right.
Remember Head is this pointer, this reference to the last commit, typically the last comment on a
branch.
So whoever head is, when we do get ahead, we'll see the changes that we've made since head.
So that includes if we try this again here, get dif head.
That includes staged and unstaged changes.
So right now, you know, we see the same exact output that we saw when I just did regular get diff.
This is showing all unstaged changes.
This is showing everything that has changed since our last commit since head.
However, if I stage something, if I do get add in, then our file is called what colors that text.
If I do get diff again now we don't see any changes.
Nothing is showing up because this is supposed to show me the difference between my working directory
and the staging area.
And right now they're the same.
But if I do get diff head, this is showing me the difference between the head and my working directory.
So now we see the same thing we were seeing earlier.
So now let's go ahead and commit.
So get commit desch and just add Indigo and then I'm going to do something different.
Now I'm going to make what should I do?
I guess I'll make a new file and this new file will be called.
It doesn't really matter, but it will be numbers.
All right.
So touch numbers, dot text.
And in this numbers file, I'm just going to add the number one to begin with, so I'll just spell it
out in all caps one.
OK, so currently numbers is untracked.
So if I try and do get diff, I'm going to see anything there.
However, if I add that new change, so get add numbers text.
Now if I do get diff head we see that since our last commis we have some new stuff.
Right.
And it's just the fact that numbers that text now exists and it has this line one inside of it, the
way that we can tell that there was nothing there before the version A is actually dev null.
That's gets way of telling us nothing compared to now having the file numbers.
So there is nothing really to compare it before, but that doesn't break it.
We just end up seeing only the additions because there only are additions.
OK, so get Dev, head shows us that, but just one more time.
Get diff on its own.
It's only showing us unstaged changes.
Nothing has been there, nothing is currently unstaged.
But if I add Vialet for example, two colors and I do get diff, we only see a diff for colors because
that's the only file that changed that has not been staged versus get diff head.
I just remind you here, numbers is staged, colors is not.
So if I do get Dev head, I see all changes staged on stage.
It doesn't matter.
Anything new in the working directory since head right and head if you ever forget and head currently
is pointing to this comment here.
So that's what we are comparing to.
So get Dev shows us all unstaged changes, get dev head shows us all changes staged and unstaged since
head.